<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Max Sharabayko Blog</title><link>https://maxsharabayko.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content on Max Sharabayko Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maxsharabayko.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bjontegaard Delta-Rate Metric</title><link>https://maxsharabayko.github.io/blog/posts/bd-rate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maxsharabayko.github.io/blog/posts/bd-rate/</guid><description>&lt;p>A video encoder can be configured in many ways: different GOP (Group of Pictures) structure,
different quantization parameters (QP) or target bitrate,
motion compensation range, etc. Furthermore, different encoders likely produce different compressed streams.
Depending on the encoder and the configuration the same source video is compressed differently, each having its own bitrate and distortion value.
Bjontegaard Delta-Rate (BD Rate) metric can be used to compare and choose the encoder or configuration, that provides the best compression results.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Examining SRT Streaming over 4G Networks</title><link>https://maxsharabayko.github.io/blog/posts/srt-4g-streaming-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maxsharabayko.github.io/blog/posts/srt-4g-streaming-2022/</guid><description>Introduction Modern mobile networks are used in a wide variety of ways, including contribution of live events from a mobile device, where the contributor can be stationary or moving. In this article we will examine the characteristics of a 4G network (and SRT behavior) with a stationary contribution source (TPLink M7000 Mobile WLAN Router) located in Northern Asia. The target ingest point is in Western Europe (Microsoft Azure cloud service). The maximum throughput declared by the Internet Service Provider (ISP) is 20 Mbps.</description></item><item><title>Next Generation Video Codecs: HEVC, VP9, Daala (2013)</title><link>https://maxsharabayko.github.io/blog/posts/nextgen-codecs-2013/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maxsharabayko.github.io/blog/posts/nextgen-codecs-2013/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nowadays video services (digital television, Internet video etc.) are a common part of our live. According to Cisco [1] mobile video traffic was 51 percent of the entire global Internet traffic by the end of 2012 and it is expected to be 66 percent by 2017.
The demand on video and its quality is very high. Since the appearance of VoIP in 1984 video resolution has increased from QCIF (176×144 pixels) to Full HD (1920×1080). Now it is evolving to 4K (3840×2160) and 8K (7680×4320) UHD. But the higher the resolution and quality is, the higher bitrate it takes.
This paper contains a general review of new video compression standards HEVC, VP9 and Daala. Their compression efficiency is studied and compared to AVC.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://maxsharabayko.github.io/blog/papers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maxsharabayko.github.io/blog/papers/</guid><description>Featured Publications Fast Rate Estimation for RDO Mode Decision in HEVC SHARABAYKO M.P., PONOMAREV O.G. Entropy. – 2014. – Vol. 16. – No. 12. – pp. 6667–6685 Availability: Entropy Journal
Publications by Chronology Contemporary Video Compression Standards. H.265/HEVC, VP9, VP10, Daala SHARABAYKO M.P., MARKOV N.G. 2016 International Siberian Conference on Control and Communications (SIBCON), Moscow, 12-14 May, 2016, pp. 1-4. Availability: IEEE Xplore
Abstract
In this paper we compare compression efficiency of the latest video coding standards H.</description></item></channel></rss>